A NIKKATSU PRODUCTION
A COLT IS MY PASSPORT
Produced by
TAKEO YANAGAWA
Based on a Story by
SHINJI FUJIWARA
Screenplay by
NOBUO YAMADA
SHUICHI NAGAHARA
Cinematography by
SHIGEYOSHI MINE
Production Design by
TOSHIYUKI MATSUI
Edited by
AKIRA SUZUKI
Music by
HARUMI IBE
Starring
JOE SHISHIDO
CHITOSE KOBAYASHI
JERRY FUJIO
SHOKI FUKAE
ZENJI YAMADA
HIDEAKI ESUMI
JUN HONGO
AKIO MIYABE
TO YOKO TAKECHI
KOJIRO KUSANAGI
RYOTARO SUGI
Featuring
TAKAMARU SASAKI
ASAO UCHIDA
ZEKO NAKAMURA
KANJURO ARASHI
Directed by
TAKASHI NOMURA
SHIMAZU
Shimazu's in the back seat
on the right.
His bodyguard, Funaki,
is on the left.
Shimazu leaves home
every morning at this time
for his office in Ginza.
He keeps a regular schedule,
only varying it
under special circumstances.
The car windows are bulletproof.
This might seem
like a good place to target him,
but those windows
are bulletproof too.
As you can see,
his bodyguard's always with him.
It'll be a tough job,
even for you.
After lunch tomorrow,
he'll be at the bank and foreign ministry,
preparing for his trip abroad.
He should finish at 2:30.
At 3:00, he'll meet with our boss
one last time in the tearoom at Kikaku.
If I do say so,
our boss is really too kind.
Why meet with Shimazu now?
In any case,
the meeting will last an hour,
so he'll return to his office
shortly after 4:00.
If he leaves his office
at his usual time, 5:00,
he'll probably go straight home.
There he'll relax
until his departure in two days.
That's about it.
What do you think?
- You've done your research.
- That's my job.
- Your information is reliable?
- Yes.
So... will you do it?
Tomorrow is Shimazu's
last full day in Japan.
If you don't kill him tomorrow,
we're in trouble.
You can do it, right?
You're our last hope.
If you botch it, we're done for.
Here's half the money
and two passports:
One for you,
and one for Mr. Shiozaki.
Please examine them.
It should all be in order.
Here are your boarding passes.
You'll get the other half
at the usual place once the job is done.
But as we agreed,
we'll need to confirm he's dead first.
I'll make sure you can't miss it.
We'd appreciate that.
As I mentioned before,
this port has long been
the Otawara gang's territory,
but recently the Shimazu gang
from Kansai has muscled its way in.
But that needn't be a problem.
We go into Kansai sometimes too.
It's stupid for us to squabble
in a small country like Japan.
We have to dream big,
so we made plans to team up
with a foreign organization.
But Shimazu got greedy.
He stole the deal from us,
and that's why -
That's why he's leaving Japan
the day after tomorrow.
We have to stop him
before he leaves.
That's enough.
Show me the way.
Very well.
I'll be going.
We're counting on you.
Don't kid around!
All done.
A lot of people order
modifications for fun,
but I don't get
many customers like you.
I can understand
souping up the engine,
but why a second brake?
Keep the change.
Thank you, sir!
SHIMAZU
I'd like to see an apartment.
- What kind?
- Have anything on the fourth floor?
We certainly do.
I'll show you.
This one is perfect.
I liked it right away.
Is that so?
Thank you very much.
This is the best building
in the neighborhood.
I'd like to look around
a bit longer.
Please take your time.
Here are the keys.
I'll most likely take it.
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
I'll be leaving now.
What do you think?
Very nice. I'd like to live
in a place like that one day.
I'll get you some tea.
Please have a seat.
Tell me:
How did he die?
No special way.
Same as they always do.
Long time no see.
What'll it be today?
This'll go straight into the crusher.
This way.
What a waste.
It's all right.
You're still young.
If you want to stay alive,
don't get too attached to your guns.
Yeah, but -
The evidence isn't the prints
on my fingers
but the bullets I pumped
into Shimazu's belly.
With the gun gone,
that's taken care of.
Here's the call.
Kamimura here.
Go ahead.
What the hell's wrong with you?
Our boss is at the police station
thanks to you!
I told you I'd make sure
you couldn't miss it.
But not when he's with our boss!
Pick up the rest of the money
and disappear!
Exactly what I plan to do.
We just received word.
One moment, please.
I can't believe it.
This is way too classy for them.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Please sign this.
- Let's go.
- Thank you.
Let's move it.
Boss...
a call's coming in.
What's up?
Don't get on the plane. The Shimazu
gang's staked out the airport.
This isn't funny.
We're boarding that plane.
Don't be stupid.
You must change your plans.
We won't let things go wrong.
We'll figure something out
and get right back to you.
Let's go.
Air France flight 305
passengers
Mr. Shuji Kamimura
and Mr. Shun Shiozaki
are requested to proceed
to the Air France counter.
Boss, they're paging us.
Screw that. We've got our passports
and boarding passes.
Hey!
Keep paging them.
We made it in time.
- Whiskey and water.
- Coming up.
Shall we go?
- What's that?
- Answer it.
Why'd you hang up?
I'm trying to help you.
You're better off
doing what I say.
Kamimura, answer!
What's going on?
- Answer!
- Hang up!
Bastard!
We worked things out.
What do we do now?
There's a Nagisakan Motel
in Yokohama.
When you get there,
call 28-3545.
A man there named Tsugawa
will take care of you.
Got that? 28-3545.
Got it.
NAGISAKAN MOTEL
Here you are.
Thank you.
We'll settle up on the usual day.
Very well. Thank you.
Who are you two?
This is the back entrance.
Room 21.
First door on the second floor.
Here it is.
What a crummy little room.
If you value your life,
don't open that window.
Last summer a guy
took a bullet in the head
when he opened that window.
A young man due to board
a ship just three hours later.
Call 28-3545.
Just say that we're here.
They'll understand.
- Shall I get it?
- Leave it.
Hello?
Room 21? Very well.
Stay put for a while.
I'll be back in touch.
Boss...
the two men Otawara mentioned
arrived at the Nagisakan.
I see.
What about a boat?
Boat 14 leaving at 9:00 tonight
connects at Pusan with the Emoru.
Get them on that one.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Senzaki of the Shimazu clan
has arrived.
Already?
Show him in.
- In here?
Of course.
Hold off a while on the boat.
I'd better hear
what Senzaki has to say.
- Oh, pardon me -
- Come in.
Sorry to intrude.
I have a special favor to ask.
What is it?
Our boss, Mr. Shimazu,
was shot earlier today.
These two did the job.
We're sure they fled here
after being blocked at the airport.
From here
they have to go by boat.
Only you can help them
with that, Mr. Tsugawa.
Have they come here?
No idea.
If they have,
they're as good as dead.
They can only be at the Nagisakan
or a couple other motels.
Can't you do that harder?
If you happen to see them...
You can put that down there.
I hope we can count on you.
- That was quick.
- How much?
Feels like 100.
What do we do?
Tonight's boat is no good.
When's the next one?
Tomorrow morning - No. 7.
- Make it that one.
- Yes, sir.
And tell them not to stay
at the Nagisakan tonight.
Can't you call them
from outside?
And draw the blinds.
Morals or money -
which will it be?
Money.
Just as I thought.
- Here's your tea.
- Thank you.
Here you go.
Evening!
Long time no see, granny!
What happened?
I haven't seen you guys in ages.
They're always
changing our routes.
Some grub, quick.
- Isn't Mina here?
- Of course she is.
That's what I like to hear!
How you doin'?
I've been driving back-to-back hauls
for 30 hours straight!
I'm dead tired too.
I need some sleep.
Ma'am, wake me up in two hours!
- Will do.
- Two hours, okay?
- I'm not deaf!
Mina!
Where have you been?
You haven't been around at all!
Mina, bring me some tea.
Listen to that guy.
Ah, that's hot!
Don't play with fire!
I'm sorry.
Don't scowl like that.
What is it?
- Are those the only occupied rooms?
- Yes.
Just what do you want?
Come on.
Knock.
Open it and go in.
- Mina!
- What about Mina?
- Are you all truck drivers?
- Keep it the hell down!
And what if I don't?
Bastards!
Check carefully.
If the 2000GT isn't here,
there must be tire marks.
Thin ones, not like truck tires.
You understand my feelings,
don't you?
After we met six months ago,
I turned over a new leaf.
I gave up drinking,
fighting, and gambling.
Make no mistake -
I'm not like the others.
I'm not kidding around.
Please be my wife.
I saved this up for you.
Please take it.
I'm happy you feel that way,
but it's impossible.
Another man once spoke...
those same words to me.
But he got himself killed.
The god of death
follows me everywhere.
Lots of pretty girls
will fall in love with you.
That's right.
Now beat it.
- Who the hell are you?
Didn't you hear me?
Beat it!
Hold on.
Still sending money
to that punk's family, aren't you?
What's his mother to you?
You can't be a fool forever.
How about coming back to me?
You can't run away.
Don't get any stupid ideas,
or I'll blow a hole in your head
like I did with that punk.
Who are you?
Where's Senzaki?
Out of my way.
All we get around here
is the riffraff.
- Where are the sewer rats?
- No sign of 'em yet.
That's because
you only went after the rats.
You gotta flush out the sewer
where they grow fat.
- Meaning?
- Just leave it to me.
But they might
come through here.
Use your head.
They won't be
coming here today.
You've got pull around here.
Take me somewhere.
Somewhere nice and fancy.
She's a looker, isn't she?
- That was harsh!
- Mina, are you mad?
Son of a bitch!
Please!
All of you, just stop!
MOTEL
- You going through Yokohama?
- That's right.
Will this get us there?
Sure.
Buddy...
isn't it time
we stopped playing tag?
I don't have the patience.
Who are you?
That's not important.
Now, how about taking me
to those sewer rats?
You can go now.
What are you going to do?
I'll wait here
for the sewer rats.
- Was that the boat?
- That's right.
- And the next one?
- No idea.
For now we have no plan.
What about our agreement?
Stop it, Shun.
Sorry about all this.
The truck
got a little banged up.
I hope this'll make up for it.
I'll set something up.
Go back to the Nagisakan.
I'll call you later.
We're back.
Come all the way
back here to get killed?
Were they here?
If you want to stay alive,
you'd better get out now.
I'm hungry.
Could you bring us some food?
Boss -
Relax, Shun.
Bring us some food.
This room is dangerous.
What do you care?
It's not your problem.
My room's better.
Nobody goes there
except the proprietress sometimes.
Come with me.
It's a bit cramped.
Boss...
what do we do now?
Hold it.
You trying to ruin this place?
Those men are wanted.
Stupid girl.
I'll fix your food now.
Boss...
we're just sitting here
waiting to be killed.
We've been
in fixes like this before,
and we got out alive
every time.
It'll be the same this time.
Still -
Shun, drink up.
It'll calm your nerves.
It's been a while.
Sing something.
A song will
make you feel better.
There's just one person
I want to meet
When I go to the wharf
Far off in the night sky
Even if you became
a twinkling star
You would whisper
That you'd wait only for me
Your star
Is a lonely little star
There's just one person
I want to meet
Chasing memories
Wandering aimlessly
"I'm sure happiness
will come soon"
You once said with a smile
But now your face
Is a ghost town in the mist
Aren't you open yet?
Bring us some food!
Right away.
- Serve the customers.
- Those men ordered first.
- He fell asleep?
- Must have been tired.
You gave him a sleeping pill.
Sometimes it's best. Especially
when you're about to be killed.
Sure you don't
need one yourself?
Are you brothers?
Why do you ask?
No reason.
I guess it makes no difference.
It was you two, wasn't it?
They found a body.
The wharf's crawling with police.
So that's why Senzaki
and his goons haven't come around.
Get out of here!
This is no place for killers!
You're one to talk.
You want people to know
you siphon gas from the trucks?
Who would do such a thing?
Stop telling lies.
Stop the chatter and take
some food to the barge.
All right!
- She mentioned a barge.
- What about it?
Forget it.
You can't get away on a barge.
Just take me there.
It's no use.
I already tried it once.
You?
Take me there anyway.
- Why?
- I want to take a look.
Don't worry about Senzaki.
With the police everywhere,
he won't come around.
- Give me something to write with.
- What for?
Poor guy won't know
where I've gone when he wakes up.
You're very thoughtful.
I envy you men...
the way you can be friends.
I was born
and raised on a barge.
It was dark and dirty
and miserable.
People called us
"the ones who live on the water."
They looked down on us
just for that.
I hated that life
ever since I was a child.
I tried to escape
so many times...
but it was no use.
Then one day
I finally did run away.
I wonder what
I was looking for.
Nothing's really changed
since I first arrived on land.
Then I met Senzaki.
I disliked him from the start,
so I ran away from him too.
But I can't seem
to get away from him.
All that's left for me is dust
and the smell of men and gasoline.
Always running away.
I'm exhausted.
We're a lot alike,
don't you think?
I'm not running away.
I'm surviving.
That's how
I've stayed alive this long.
If I hadn't fought
when I was a kid,
I'd have starved to death.
I'll make it out this time too.
Now that everything's worked out,
yesterday's bloody incident
seems like a mere dream.
Eh, Mr. Shimazu?
Violence isn't the only way
to increase our gang's power.
My father
never understood that.
Your father
was a very good man,
but you and I understand
each other much better.
I think business will go very well
now that we've teamed up.
There's nothing to fear now.
Everything will be just fine.
Just one thing: I want the head
of the rat who killed my father.
That's right.
He's still alive.
What shall we do?
I'll take care of it.
I won't let you down.
Where is that rat?
At the Nagisakan.
I'll be on my way.
Good. Very good.
- We're here.
- Thanks for bringing that, Mina.
Not at all, Captain.
How's the game?
This guy's winning, as usual.
You can see it on his face.
I'll win a little back
before we set out this afternoon.
Ah, please join us.
He's not here to play.
Is he your boyfriend?
Mina's a good girl.
If you make her cry,
these guys'll kill you.
You're leaving today?
Wasn't it tomorrow?
We work for a crappy company.
They're always changing cargo
and destinations on us.
No job's ever gone
as scheduled.
Captain, could you take me
on your boat?
You?
Me and one other person.
We have passports.
Passports!
Makes no difference
one way or the other.
Hide in a corner of the hold.
We'll drop you off wherever you want.
Is the other person Mina?
No, it's not.
I won!
Damn! Again?
My rotten luck!
- Is there room for me too?
- Of course.
There's always room for you,
but you always stand us up.
Buddy, don't believe her if she says
she's running away with you.
She always stays behind
at the last minute.
Those raised here
can't go anywhere else.
NAGISAKAN
Son of a bitch!
Don't try anything funny.
Tell me where your friend is!
Bastard!
Fine with me
if you don't want to talk,
but you'll pay for it.
So get ready!
I don't know anything.
Tsugawa asked me to put them up.
If you don't like it,
go tell Tsugawa!
You idiot.
Tsugawa's the one
looking for them.
Just today, he and our boss
Shimazu decided to join forces.
So you better talk
if you know what's good for you.
- What is it?
- Get down!
You bastards!
Let me go!
We have a problem.
There's one rat left.
Where was Shun?
A dirty room in the attic.
I knew it was Mina.
So they'll try to escape by sea.
The rat's probably
on a barge right now.
A barge?
That's bad news.
That's outside my territory.
I can't do anything.
Why not?
You see...
those outcasts who work
those barges stick together
and don't listen
to a thing we say.
There must be some way
to flush the rat out.
Hello.
All right.
It's from the Nagisakan.
They say Mina came back alone.
I'll go.
Where are you going?
- I'm leaving.
- Again?
This time it's really good-bye.
Really?
You tried to escape
a long time ago too,
but you never made it.
Well, not me.
I'm getting out.
Together with that wanted man?
No.
They took his young friend away.
They beat him up bad.
They'll kill the other one too.
Still leaving?
Yes.
Not so fast.
Come here a minute.
Take it.
It's Senzaki.
Listen...
tell Kamimura that
his young friend's life is in our hands.
If he doesn't want him killed,
he'd better come to Tsugawa's.
Where's Shun?
- He took off.
- Took off?
Did those men show up?
Yes, but I asked the old lady
to bring him here.
It'll be fine.
He'll be here soon.
What are you hiding?
Tell me the truth.
What do you mean?
Let's go!
- Stop!
- Hey, don't be so rough.
Cut the crap!
They went to the Nagisakan.
When you got there,
Shun was gone, right?
I told you: The old lady
will bring him for sure.
What are you doing here?
You don't belong here.
I know.
I just want to talk to that guy.
Take me to him.
I'm unarmed.
Search me.
All right. Come on.
Go ahead.
What a shame.
You almost got away.
Why have you come here?
She didn't tell you?
Then it's a good thing I came.
We've got your young pal.
He's our hostage.
But it's me you want.
Yeah.
Now will you come with me?
Not so fast.
Let Shun go.
When does the ship sail?
In three hours.
Very well.
We let the little rat get on it.
Then what?
Nothing happens
until the ship leaves.
I won't run away or hide.
In exchange,
you promise to let Shun go.
We won't lay a hand on you
until the ship leaves.
You trust this bastard?
You gotta feel for her.
What are you
gonna do with me?
What are you planning?
Tell me!
Little rat...
stop your hollering
and take a good look.
We have no use for you anymore.
Go somewhere far away
and disappear.
You're up to something.
Hurry up!
Boss, it's a trap!
Shun, we came to an agreement.
Come on.
Hurry up!
Shun.
Say a word and I shoot.
Mina, is it true?
Come on.
Set his mind at ease.
Come on. Please.
Come on up.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
- Boss.
- Shun.
That's better.
Please take care of him.
How could you agree
to something so stupid?
Let's go.
Take care now.
I just got off the ship.
Like I said,
I won't run away or hide.
If you want
a deserted spot to kill me,
I'll be at the landfill
tomorrow at 7:00 a.m.
Fine.
See you at the landfill at 7:00 a.m.
Where are we?
Boss!
How many will there be?
Three... five...
maybe even ten men.
With a pistol I'd get one or two,
three at the most.
A shotgun?
With one well-aimed shell,
I could get two of them.
Might not kill them,
but they'd be out of action.
Then there's the Beretta.
Double-barreled.
It can take out four men.
This is a shotgun.
It's often used for hunting...
because it scatters shot
over a wide area.
He might try to kill us
all at once with one of these.
Please excuse us while we play
a recording to cover the noise.
That's really something!
We've also considered
the possibility he'll use a rifle.
This is a.45 caliber,
the largest and most destructive.
Let's see what one of these
does to the car.
She cost me a fortune,
but she's a sweetheart,
isn't she?
A real tank.
We'll ride in this tomorrow
to watch them trap the rat.
Just as I thought:
A shotgun.
Please take a look.
Go!
THE END
Subtitles by
Subtext Subtitling, Los Angeles